Zhuoyue (Joey) Wang

(217)-979-3885 | zhuoyue_wang@berkeley.edu | 450 W 42nd St, New York, NY 10036 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhuoyuewang/

SUMMARY

Results-driven Software Engineer with a solid foundation in **infrastructure development**, specializing in **database kernel**, with over **3 years of experience** and an **M.Eng. degree in Computer Science** and strong skills in **C/C++/Python**. Keen on applying expertises to tackle new challenges within the trading/hedge fund/finance industry.

CURRENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Member of Technical Staff

July 2020 -

Oracle

Redwood City, CA/New York City, NY

Specialized in C language for Oracle SQL In-memory database kernel development, with a focus on memory storage

- Primary Scope of Work: Storage-Pool-Member (Persistent Memory (PMEM) Storage Component):
 - Experienced owner of SPM code who effectively collaborated with engineers from diverse teams to ensuring the seamless integration and functionality on the component within the database system.
 - Designed and implemented reliable, performant memory allocation/deallocation routines with multi-thread/multiinstance concurrency and recovery support at the terabyte scale.
 - Developed highly efficient background memory management solutions, optimizing space performance and reducing client operation latency through techniques like deferred memory clearing, RDMA region auto extend, memory defragmentation, and log/user data region rebalancing.
- Selective Project: The Engine Out-Of-Resource (EngOor) project:
 - Launched an infrastructure project addressing memory space constraints when consuming data, resulting in improved diagnostics and possible mitigations.
 - Designed the infrastructure framework, collaborating with cross-functional teams. The aspects include Resource Monitoring, Automatic Mitigation & Logging and Alerts.
 - Successfully implemented the infrastructure and served as the primary POC for framework-related inquiries.
 - Presented the project to a large audience of approximately 100 people, including Head of Oracle SQL Org.
- Non-Technical: Revised new hire guide on Oracle Database kernel development, resulting in reduced learning curves for incoming team members. Mentored junior hires and organized team outings events.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Simple TD Ameritrade Trading Bot (C++) (Ongoing)

 Developing TDA account authentication and implementing core functionalities of the Account class, including balance, margin, and equity tracking.

Simple Binance Crypto Trading Bot (Python)

- Developed and deployed a crypto trading bot that executes buy and sell orders based on a predefined trading strategy.
- Integrated with the Binance API and utilized the web socket protocol for real-time OHLC price data. Configured technical indicators and created bot instances for multiple cryptocurrency pairs.
- Designed a crypto trading workflow encompassing decision-making for opening and closing long or short positions.

PAST WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern

June 2019 – August 2019

Wayfair

Boston, MA

• Developed the 3D product scene selection feature (PHP, JavaScript, MySQL), and reworked on the related schemas in the internal catalog system database (500,000 records), achieving a notable 30% improvement in query efficiency.

Software Engineer Intern

January 2019 - May 2019

NextCapital

Chicago, IL

Utilized full-stack technologies (Ruby on Rails, MySQL) to build web pages in the investment portfolio platform.

Software Engineer Intern

August 2018 – December 2018 Chicago, IL

Trustwave Chicago, IL

• Designed and implemented the LogCollection and HashContent components in C++ for Apache MiNiFi, an open-source

framework, improving data flow capabilities in ETL pipelines.

Integrated Apache MiNiFi, Kafka, Elasticsearch, Kibana and Logstash to enable real-time streaming analytics on files,

delivering valuable insights and analysis.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

GPA: 3.72/4.0

Master of Engineering in Electrical Engineering & Computer Science

August 2019 – May 2020 **GPA: 3.91/4.0**

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

August 2016 – May 2019

SKILLS

Languages: C, C++14/17/20, Python 2/3, Java, React, SQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Ruby, PHP, Shell, R Tools: Linux, Unix, Git, MySQL, NoSQL, Docker, Eclipse, Android Studio, Xcode, AWS, RESTful API, ElasticSearch/Kibana/Logstash, Apache MiNiFi, Kafka, Ruby on Rails, JIRA, Tableau, Oauth

Skills: data structure, system programming, full-stack development, data analytics, machine learning, distributed system, parallel computing, statistics & probability, calculus, linear algebra, basic accounting & finance, Blackjack, Texas Hold'em Accomplishment: SAT score: 2080; University Honor (Top 3% in college); UC Berkeley Scholarship Recipient; Engaged in stock trading with an annual return of 30% (in the best year); Served as a board member in a college club